Matthew Gonzalez

Full-Stack Software Developer

gonzalez.matthew.steven@gmail.com (213) 401-8303

<u>_inkedIn</u> GitHub

Accomplished security professional with a solid background in personnel and security operations management, spanning over 7 years. Distinguished as an honored graduate from multiple training schools, they excel at effectively overseeing valuable equipment and training systems worth \$100,000. Currently embarking on a transformative journey into the tech world, they bring their expertise as a full-stack developer, proficient in multiple programming languages and frameworks.

Technical Skills

HTML - CSS - Bootstrap - JavaScript - ES6 - jQuery - Ajax - JSON - RESTful API - REST API - Maven - Java SE - Java EE (Servlets, JSP, J2EE) - File I/O - MVC - Spring Boot - Hibernate - MySQL - Thymeleaf - Object-Oriented Programming (OOP) - Test-Driven Development (TDD) - Version Control with Git - Paired Programming - Agile Methodologies - Debugging - AWS Deployment - Apache TomCat - Unit Testing (JUnit) - C#

Exposure to: Agile Management Tools - KanBan for Workflow - Project Management Tools - Github Pages - NPM - Scrum Stand Up - Documentation - Spring Framework - Unity

Soft Skills

Collaborative - Peer Review - Innovative - Strong Communication Skills - Teamwork - Builds Relationships - Initiative - Analytical - Flexibility - Reliable - Integrity - Work Independently - Visualization - Virtualization - Willingness to Learn - Collaborate - Problem-Solving Skills - Research Skills - Dedicated - Competitive - Self-motivated - Committed - Team Player - Innovative - Independent - Written and Oral Communication Skills - Culture - Fast Paced

Development Projects

Capstone Project Name: Github Repository

Worked collaboratively with a group of developers to design, plan, build, and deploy a mobile-responsive full-stack web application. We began with my idea and through collective development we created wireframes as well as a kanban board to follow progress. Designed database structure, and worked on backend development, and deployment using AWS.

Skills: Paired Programming, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Java, JavaScript, Spring Boot, Spring Boot Security, API.

PadLister: Github Repository

A simplified version of Craigslist that allows users to post and browse advertisements for animals. The project provides a functional and user-friendly platform for posting and browsing advertisements, while also providing me with experience in web development, database management, and software testing. Responsible for backend and full CRUD with users and ads.

Skills: Paired programming, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Spring, MySQL, and jQuery.

Weatherly: Github Repository

A weather application that gives the forecast for locations around the world. The application is designed with a clean and intuitive interface that allows users to quickly and easily access the information they need. The application makes use of the latest weather data to provide hourly and daily forecasts.

Skills: HTML, CSS, jQuery, AJAX, and OpenWeatherMap API

Military Experience

US Navy - Great Lakes, IL/ Saratoga Springs, NY / Norfolk, VA *Petty Officer Second Class* / Jun 2014 - Apr 2021

- Revamped and managed a diverse crew of over 200 sailors in a variety of roles, including administration, electrical engineering, police tactics, inventory management, and leadership. Multiple inspection scores significantly improved as a result of skillful management.
- Volunteered 150+ hours with local homeless shelters in Chicago, food banks in New York, and veteran services in a hospice in Great Lakes. Also worked with Navy Marine Corp. Relief Society to raise \$1,000 plus dollars for sailors and their families.
- Skillfully maintained daily communication with Officers and higher-ranking officials to ensure seamless connectivity among personnel, facilitating uninterrupted mission operations.

Professional Experience

Starbucks - Saratoga Springs *Barista / Oct 2019 - Mar 2021*

- created seasonal coffee drinks that attracted repeat customers and drove a 35% increase in sales of specialty menu items.
- cultivated a warm, welcoming environment and developed strong relationships with both new and returning customers to deliver legendary customer experiences.
- operated cash drawer for a daily average of over 100 transactions. processed payments using cash and credit cards.

Great Neck Doggie Daycare - Saratoga Springs

Dog Handler / Mar 2021 - August 2021

- helped evaluate and assess the behavior and development of the dogs during training sessions for approval for the facility.
- efficiently shared information about the development of their dog's training with the dog's owners and suggested training methods.
- used methods of positive reinforcement to motivate the pets of clients to behave in a desired way.

Education

Codeup

Certification of Completion

Oct 2022 - Apr 2023

This 5-month coding boot camp teaches full-stack software development through 670 contact hours of hands-on technical training (20% more time than 4-year degree majors require). Students hone skills in modern web technologies, computer science, software engineering, and application architecture while gaining project experience with pair programming, debugging, troubleshooting, agile project management, user stories, feature lists, UI/UX, wireframing, and relational database design.